this course is a
yeah every year it's it's been done so
it'll be somebody else
the material over stay online no so it's
not the disappear the idea is to keep it
whether or not i'm here and i'll be
imprisoned notes
and start using a lot myself
right let me go ahead and get started
i'd say we've got some announcements
the first one is you
most of you probably heard by now i'm
going to be going to do hope to work on
allusions
i'll be a full-time g_i_ estate engineer
starting in january time with you for
the rest of the semester i'm not running
off on you
so if you collect the chemistry i watch
of the symmetry but not till
next summer player
yet so he gave me and cooperate with
your data
that means are we trying to figure out
how did this kind of uh... dangerous
stuff isn't done yet so there's lots and
lots of it make more
datewise
shall you are the more that you can
generate because you can ping faster
so the shallow stuff is the hard stuff
what's that there's tatum issues and how
do you plan it but uh... sure if you
look right now it hurt
they usually a picture of some water
between the chemistry in the shorter
kinda buffer that
so will be tried
and then also doing lots of dr
and polygon tech data sets
this just came out by just saw this
the national science foundation this is
their sample and data policy
so the pediatric talked about their
procedures for what you've got to do
with your data
linked to in this class
the noah persons of that
and talked a little bit about that
not nearly as much as i would like to
hear too late to document the term
anti-theft hopping about
how they think you should work with data
i did no more than just for estimate
but it's probably a good pointer at
least a good start in vocabulary in
terms of mentioned it sets
and i think i want to point out to you
guys that
i didn't hear intel weighed way into my
career and i think it's really important
is the party tak
distance for research vessel technicians
these are people who work upon
ships all over the world and
miles of these people knowing what you
are also
working on shore and don't you could see
those people who all care about the
workings of chips and it covers
everything from
people try to figure out what kind of
when trying to put on their cgp or how
do welding on the ship
or how to manage the data systems
and they have a conference once a year
infection this week
on the front for some missing it
but there's some really great
discussions about managing data at
processing multi beam
and on their website
i'm giving you a couple links to things
i think they're extremely have this
document debo
which is got summoned very helpful
documents that you may use in your
classes as background tale for
so i think that's a mistake
so it's important to know about this
trip and a mailing list and if you get
really stuck when you're you've
graduated out of seeing you need help
figuring something out
this is a great bunch of folks who want
to answer peoples questions
know what i want that
webs you is up
fox forty is the
free open source software
conference on geospatial
so that number four means the word apple
or in english
these are geospatial people
and they have a conference every year
it's been all over the world it's been
in uh...
spare portugal last year this year was
in denver next year it's somewhere in
the asia i think
the video from this year has gone up so
if you're interested in more of these
topics
and i just give you a direct link to one
of them
frank former damn is their lead author
for
do you know
that used racial data traction library
we've been using
he gave a talk about performance and
speed on
g doll with rafters so when you start
getting big datasets
working here the first machine were with
the king fairly easy problems
cooper the virtual machine because
they're trying to
spinner time learning not waiting for
the computer finish
you've been looking at how do you hewitt
big images and so
his test inmates
in sixteen k by sixteen k cells
and he was trying to figure out how to
read out the fastest
so that's an interesting things in there
says a lot going on out there
there's tons of tools that we haven't
talked about in here just want to give
you a sense that
there's more than just what's going on
here is a big community of a lot of
people who are very excited talk to
beginners
and experts alike
accuracy also to go for with lifetime in
this time if you got the feeling
uncomfortable with bits bytes doubles
and floats in injuries
throughout three youtube videos that i
thought
gave you his defensive picture
wondering about that invites you wanna
obey our discussion of 'em
these people actually taken serious time
to go through and it's about thirty
minutes in the talk about this invites
and three p detail me show you a lot of
examples
the first one is very
reaction is pretty good i think and then
users who are definite polish but think
that good
despite the fact that wikipedia isn't
agreed academic sources
there are some really great articles on
wikipedia about
particular equations and map techniques
and
computer science terminology so i threw
in the injured two fourteen point
and the binary number system pages i
think they're actually pretty good
references
flew there if you uh...
who would need more
sublets
jump into a new topic then give the book
with you
so we're gonna cut it advocates in the
book depends holding up here
from the cure-all
and we're gonna just departs helen upon
we're not gonna try too hard
we register often see it once
commemorated into it more down the road
has called material which is one of the
many version control system so if you've
seen tracked changes in word
charging that word is directly copy from
pollution control systems it is
it's not as powerful as i think you'll
see here
it's about picking a documents and
making the changes keeping track of why
and how and when things changed and
being able to
diverging ideas like if you you are
working in a car to get you might have a
different idea of how to approach it and
you might split off from each other for
a little bit
figure approaches that come back
and how do you then
get your cue
few ideas to come back to better
enjoying into one final project
this schedule is designed for exactly
that
that they were not going to use it for
very much
for justin he is a small bit of
instability
but hope will give you a sense that it
ten
or take are fairly easy
and there are parts in there that will
definitely in mind around a few times as
you try to figure out how does
to people who work together
where they'd you've been working
separately for a month or two if that's
not easy
what the coolest
but here for a visa to pull down
the notes for class
and will use them from now on to keep
the notes from class on your virtual
machine up to date
and so what you can do it
once you've got set up
all you have to do is going to
directorate notes are
and there's one command to update those
notes for the latest version to get the
latest class
and you don't have to worry about
running around doing it that you get
or curl to find some file or doing
downloading
and web browser
bheji here is that
it knows where they come from knows
their history
and you can say please just get the
latest version and make this problem
so we're going to go ahead and
pull the notes onto your machines now
the section we will do all the today
minute we're a go into computers from
now on
and then i'll put the command in each
class that updates to get the latest
version so that that
the new stuff
there
there was certainly is some information
on material so we use to something
called subversion or sdn
and a lot of people in this building
have subversion repository for the keep
their stuff
n c thomas train transition material
that's a great question because that
reminds me to say that
there's that lots of different virgin
control tools
subversion is great if your on lamp with
the internet all the time
material and get
are two new ones that are designed such
that you don't have to have internet all
the time
it's ok bfc
and to make changes in check and then
because he checked them in locally and
then you can have more four father
towards the fencing for nice together so
when you get back to an internet
connection
you kid and pushed into the sea calm
repository from your local
and that means that using track changes
if you go
at sea without internet
with separation
we have people who come back
they've done a month's worth of changes
that could be
ten thousand lines of code and
fire ten thousand winds attacks that
they've written at sea
and they have one big chains with all
those in
it might be something on biology
something on the thesis something on
yet another note something about
administration you know it's just
falynn related
records one giant change in the third
thing about these things is it's great
to be able to act the why did i make
that change
so when you go back to six months later
and say
you know this isn't working out in your
republican out that's why i made this
decision and that's actually tracking
here
so will see some of that and i think ill
hopefully start liking it
some of this is just sort of my habits
to arthritis planos
so i tend to make a director called
projects
check things out under project so i
kinda have a sense that those are
version controlled
will make a directory called projects
to clear europe
selector
projects
we're going to projects
in case you don't happen on your
machines
you can do you
this comming here to install material
which is also known by that
very similar word mercury and some
before his aides g
so will say studio helped get
installment cure-all
and for me it's a release all that
think it's install all of your machines
and now we can say age t
clone and clone means go out grab a
repository and quote your local
testified
dolly the sheet wasn't
yes here cloning
writes an acidic copy that you are a
land
and also unit where you can get this
command
so when you enter
giving it a bunch of warnings about
certificates that's fsl troubles not a
big deal
and then it's checked out stuff if you
do an ls dash l_a_
in that directory
so what we've got now is any research
tools directory
ever treat them and written over here
through the state tree research tools
and you'll see
uh... the graphical representation of
what's in there
and so you'll see all the possible to
actually hiding here
and if you
running up a command if there's new
files in their analyst appear
eighty handles the mention of those
files for you
door about
so if we went into research tools an in
class
you know if that show
we have way too much stuff but then we
could say less twenty-two
haifong
just when she was in town
and we're now looking at today's notes
so they're not sitting where we want
them but with us leaving here more copy
them
from this location into our working area
to work with them today
i'm also very tight history so you can
take a quick peter what i've done
to start updating the major projects
we went cd into projects
reinstalled material
we did this thing called cloned with a
cure-all
when the reasons i got to go faster and
i copied that u r l effect that it's
pretty slow that tide
i took a look around and in a tree
wish to receive uh... file structure
nicole area with a
funky little graphical form
and i went in there took a look
a seed into research tools plus plus
and then itin alice
and then called last uh...
knows this vote directory okay so do the
control you
okay syrian projects do analysis
national we'll see what you've got a new
directory
equities here in projects rehearsal
projects
does united bank records for backup
juicy dot dot will go one retreat
now do analysis national
and now you've got clarkston signaling
the classic and they should be almost
files
so now
bring scroll down just a little bit
to the setup section
so personal to a cd
just to go back
to your home directory so for the
repeatedly d
and then home
research tools
will see in the projects
pendency into research tools
in this directory
and material command to update and get
the latest files is
so the first lady was clone was clone
that repository for a verdict is this
computer
and now you're into a poll to grab the
latest changes
she just a case g and then though
to work poll
loans
if i would somehow sneaking onto the
computer some stuff to change out
hopefully should say that nothing has
changed or
there might be a hacker myaccount comes
out
we're just doing that so you see the
commands and then
we're gonna run the eighty-four command
every time you come to class
here and i commend you get the latest
version
drippings allotted to zipping class or
some critical
problem aka quick fix it
i could push those changes up to the
server
and then we could have been brought them
back and
so they have did you pull and press
enter
you see two warnings these are after so
warnings
that you need to ignore
they're really kind of annoying
to bc lies right here worth is searching
for changes new changes found
were not surprised because i haven't
been in the file overdoing it
i'm going to go jump to a web browser
need i think it's fall along here follow
along with a web browser or you can
just watch
big deal
heeheehee
it's going to give you a conflict
it's going to say i don't know what to
do intel you deal with this i'm
disgusted here and say no
cynical put up and you can hear and
paste and that your own
so this is our website
pickpocket there's a whole bunch of
companies that were to provide
reversion controller polish works for
you there's also one here's the comet
you can use
you can use several one or none of them
depending on what you feel like doing
a lot of them have free accounts and so
if we're doing here if you do open
source code in your project isn't huge
like i'm not going to be checking in the
audio and video files for this class in
here because they made me think a lot of
money
because there's a huge files
we were to go here
they thought that this company says said
you know i will let you go ahead and
have free accounts where you can store
stuff
in your pocket korea
and there's lots of things you'll be
able to deal with these websites we
could share you keep you've gotta find a
mistake in my coach of the way they're
also you guys later on
to send me the pics
and then i can
review it please call the poor request
and then i can say yep i like it or
now are rejected by
here's what i was here instead
so it's got a whole lot of collaboration
tools
everything connects
so you can see working on class thirty
four minutes ago two hours ago four
hours ago
and each of these revisions
you can click on a particular one doubts
evil say
minor cleanup
guy and in there
they'll actually have
highlighted
what i've changed
and so there's a music commented blues
still need a bit but that i've been
using something called get house instead
to similar service
it'll show you colored
the things about everything in green
but you can see here are trying to
figure out
board would like to turn some of my text
into a footnote and i wasn't trying to
write a footnote has turned a report
i fight on the same
you can see what is changing i think
your account about where i create
outsourced walk
anti-fur activists were flock was placed
on them i try to export it said
how your source block is messed up i
don't know what the colored eyes so
for fix it
and so you can see all of my changes
over time and you can go back to
different versions
you can comment on it you can tell me
that my revisions thought or it was good
or you know you'd rather see something
else
and there's all kind of different things
that you can do you you can follow it to
you can get notice whatever something's
changed
that command here and what did he call
in to get onto your computer
they put that on every single page
so if you are not command in terminal on
a different computer
ill grab the same repository incurable
of machine
i don't expect at this point do you have
a good feel for what material is
but for now
you'll be seeing the if there's a price
out there that you want to work with
when you want to get the latest version
of it
and have her pottery like this you can
run a command
to grab at repository and then you'll be
able to update info along with people
for building it
with the practice that's a really good
question
there's probably a lot of thought
they're very all over the place on that
if you think about tumi open-source
projects they tend to be a an individual
project
i've seen people mistake
all of the work that they do
across offers a different opportunities
one giant repository they have a
directory and respect for each one
i've seen people who have
hundreds of limited or piloto reason
like each one of the plot
i kinda think that's a little
you know it really is your own personal
preference and who you're working with
if it's on your own
you have total flexibility so i would
you think is good enough
non-stop it working in a group
oftentimes
the group decides with resulting so if
you're working on
topic with the consistent set of people
that might be a repository
good thing that we might do sometimes is
split off the big files
because they take a long time to update
can i get really frustrating
role and i try to put six gigabytes of
images and models and whatnot from jews
who we into a popular ones
and hours later
we decided that would really a bad idea
it was still burning away on the
uploading the talmud torah
almost as long to me this was really
frustrating
so sometimes footing in terms of size
organization each the books on these
topics usually give you some sort of
sense
and and i think
it shouldn't be too huge and should be a
sort of logical thought
is something you had to try and see
so for me
this class
all the org wrote notes and
abortion and be able to big so i've not
with the man's repositories you can see
a decision i've made that this class is
just going to be the notes for the
classes
dot videos and then the separate work
files that living outside of class
tough question
and i think if you very good solid
answer because i don't think that the
picket line
it's a tool that can be used and also
the different ways to you
you could put the files on it locally
with this one that might work unlike
subversion which had to go to an
external server
which is why the sixty-two by stupid
forever
kill that webpage
and let's go do some more aspect
processing
and a cv back to home retreat
we're gonna make their
dash p
phil dislodge class twenty-two
press enter
and in the cd
into filled splotch class
twenty-one
hit and sitting at the time to find a
break things up a little bit anti peter
t_v_
and make sure that you see
in that directory we're gonna go ahead
and go round
first verdict
grabbed locally
the uh...
workbook probably hand sold to you
filled with slash
projects
research tools sorry tab
class
twenty-two
and there's our or final
and period for the current directory
breast cancer
after u_n_ allies
you'll see we have justin or file on
there
sims is not a repository of will just go
ahead and grab
unit curl command again
aspect example we have been warned
compressive
you've got it
and so now if we do know a special
and we should see here we have our or
file and ever civil aspect
and feel free run the indy five some
again just to make sure that we have the
right file
the five
and it looks like to have sample file
penis me i'm going to change things
between the hot spots in them
if you have the mac started
a great way to make sure that you have
the right word file open the right
location this week and safety max
clients dash dash no dash weight
and then twenty huge happens
and is scheduled imax please go
startup
that file
editing
and surgery ido a couple of you still
have a problem with
not having yet dot max file for the
correct that we haven't solved it
for you you have your control x control
after an open the file
and go see the answer
plus twenty
but if you have it working
and hit enter here
your you max
state class twenty two
and we should be good to go
i'm gonna jump down in new york file
using control that's animus they i papon
and i'm getting down to start by pipe on
a terminal
so at this point i'm gonna hide firefox
communing more
it'll be just doing i pythons terminal
plus
will go ahead type
clears just a hide everything because
it's getting
noisy vimal type
hi pipeline to enter
where they go into that water again so
we can keep a journal of what's going on
who'll say log start
dash co dash
flaunt dash class class twenty-two used
up time
breast cancer
and now we have a log files
pete you know a special you'll see that
you have
log plus twenty five
so we're gonna
definitely use these
three models today's early steuben
source they import struct import num
five
and import map
we've got those rated gal
we're gonna play a little bit with the
file directly in my paper on
so we did last time
aspect
underscore file equals
open
essay on tab
you get your sample dot aspect
and then hit enter
and aspect
data equals
aspect
file taught lead
two princes teletype history two seconds
you can see the whole list of commands
lefevre history
and you can see one through eight
of the contents we've done so far
awesome
uninformed
you know actually right
twenty princes
answer
uh...
control of the
accurate
i think that definitely want out of
those things
applicants but i i i thought
you got to the whose commander
when type losing to make sure you got a
very bold in there
to uh... pvd
and george interaction
a standard
can cause that we know just quit for
orange acts
and terminal
to split there
yet just kill it
i would say reboot the virtual machine
completely
with the columbine or you may have to
kill it and you have to work and
catching up
there's something really weird
there for you to answer
we feel we've got are really horrible
looking deliveries trucked departs
and we were working on building a
function
it's going to load up this data
what i think they're lovely days duty
and asking questions
outside of class to tell me
that i'm not covering something well
enough
and so you got it done that and i want
to go back to functions again
and make sure that you guys have a good
sense of how
arguments and parameters are passed in
the functions will give it another go
and i hope that helps surrender these
notes
with whose
where the a section functions and
arguments
and i'm giving you a link to a couple
to web pages that i think our okay
and utube video which it
definitely works to go through
as for the first time
horrific read a file called some of our
top clients
stock in the very exciting
ever to pretend to set the frequency of
the sonar
where decreases filed as a symbol for
strength there is going to work through
our guest house and all that
and i think this will help you guys
make sure that you've got pregnant
passing
i must put this control excuse
animate it you can't relax control ap
pants on in class twenty-two anonymous
types sonar thuc hien
pressed enter
so not got my saurabh
doctype rather than a work on
trading here
it has the
please write the senate
to recreate our first function
is the beginning of defining a function
the function name is gonna be set
frequency
to parentheses
a medical and and this is the first one
to find the function
and for all functions is to be very
similar
you'll change the name and later on
we'll see what we put in the plant the
seeds
inside that function
will save print
setting
frequency
and then we'll put a comment
rate code here
cues that the frequency
we are not going to write that column as
we have no solo to talk to you
but i figured example this for some or
something you might actually have to do
is
more helpful
say that control x control s
we're gonna run that scripts sophie go
gains or a pipeline terminal
type tell us
we should see
sonar top-line
and i i thought has that run command
reviewed so ron sonar
anybody think
they know what's going to happen
with the apple might be
no
i heard one nothing heard no argument
yep
we actually never call the function
so i'm guessing ritzy nothing
yet runs at least doesn't
it was there
but some of academia as frustrating as
an error message or more frustrating
because we don't know what happened
and the trick is we need to call our
function for the can actually use it
cities grow a little bit i have the
example how do you that
andaman also add a little bit
documentations
for help so
the following
creates the function
the deposition work for define
and then going to call that function
subset
frequency
q parentheses
and then
favor with control x control arms
and let's rely on that
so it says
setting frequency
right so that we've got
a function call so
it's very similar syntax between the
call
right here and definition
he's had the extra dept
and then the colin thing started
if you want to set this frequency horny
also that record number we need to have
an argument we can pass in
into the function
so in our function name
we need to be able to go in here
and passing something because in the
sixty parentheses
it's going to be our very ball that
we've been using here
to set the frequency
so what we can do
it's a at barton q
for ruling or freak
and then bull add some very important
role here
that really sucks the frequency kelly
full issues that variable to print out
what our frequency would be that we're
trying to set
so let's go ahead and say this
control execute reliance
the key thing here is that that
frequency variable is local to the
function
after review has nothing to do with
anything else lined up auction doesn't
exist anyone else
and let's try reading that and see what
happens
and we had a really nice error message
today
no the trouble is is that we now have
operator or uh... argument or function
we haven't called it with anything in
here
so we're trying to call for june fifth
need some data
we're not getting anything so if it's at
in python there's a really nice feature
if you know the default value were the
most common values going to be used in
the function
you can step back has a default value
inside of this parameter
perhaps a very common frequency for
stars in deep water
twelve killer hurts
this is not your shallow water sewer
but if we have a tocqueville hurts or we
can set that to be our default
and we can try running this again
what's gonna happen if it comes to hear
there's no argument in here and says
okay
for and take that the faltering use
inside
so we should see
this print right here is then take that
the pot by u_n_ printed out
sunset run again
and now we have
setting frequency twelve thousand
animated dissonant notes because we
should always return units and i didn't
about that
self-knowledge efforts on this
so that gives you lucia default value
but what if we want to go inside
ourselves
we then you need to do is we passing a
parameter c has been doing so wat i'm
just trying to be picture what that's
about you've done it for a few weeks
negative
cvg and hope will reinforce the idea of
passing parameters
so what if we want
uh... twenty-four killer sort when four
thousand hurts sonar
favour and try to get it
so what this will do is say passing a
parameter
this is the first number gets assigned
to the first value and that twenty four
thousand will go in
to their frequency variable are at
foreign key on
with iran
and now says that in frequency twenty
four thousand
sold out if that's the passing a
parameter
now what if we want to use that for a
variable so this election show effect
variables existed different faces
and what if i say
mine
sonar
frequency a for a few
equals
fifteen killer to fifteen thousand
amble past and
mine
sonar separate human
stay back
anticipates it takes a very real name
and then a nexus out here that you're
using a parameter
doesn't have to be the same name
as what's inside here what matters is
the position that matches up the first
argument to the first hurdle he within
your definition
so give better run
runs alarm and you should see
where this is very exciting we set our
sonar to publicly frequencies here
one last thing is first showed up the
power being able to pass arguments
around and do some fun things
is that you can do things like treatment
table of values that you might want to
use so you have a list of some of our
jeanne lawler frequencies
if you create a little odd
dictionary
it's got all possible values and it's a
sonar
frequency or free cable
equals let's curly braces start a
dictionary
right curly braces and dictionary
and then we have kian value inside
so we can say
d_m_ one twenty two which is a kong's
first aren't
twelve thousand
and then
and it's in which is uh...
because we have some fun profiler or
a single beam
at the same will be not some watermark
char or
scene of the polls
and that
one for diseases often use but that is
three point five kilometers
and then we call this
we can say
sonar
freak table
and then have to say
in quotes
mason is pronounced like it has been ok
it does
so here we gotta look up
of knutson
our frequency table
well we all might remember
dot number one might use it so often
that we feel it's no big deal
if you start going to someone else's
coordinate got like twelve thousand
hearing three five bear
you don't know what they meant
what they were intending on that code
so this way you know that someone was
trying to set the frequency to be the
frequency consider fall for anything
so if you try to oftentimes their coach
communicate more than just the actual
number attract communicate the reason
the meaning behind them
sold on that one
and it works out
three thousand five hundred hurts
so that's just a quick review of
functions
we can also do you one of the finest
will be having a second parameter
things are coming into your scripts
we're going for that
down the road in this series of
but that's that's right
l having everest best-prepared
they forget their walters copyrights
patents do it by three times company
will be able to passing through its what
you do if you read it
a set of functions that hanoi file name
and then outside of that you walk
through much of filings
so we're going were aiming to get there
so if we had a second very well that
might be named
equals
unknown as our default
named is
ceramic a passing the second variable
its day
harvey
super slow
so what if they do is it's gonna match
up
our first input
argument
with the first variable in our
definition
and the second one will get matched up
the second one
right where you can have more for one
thing that is not a point of one
running
and so setting frequency thirty five pst
name is harvey super slow
so that sucked quick or minero functions
don't feel like you it's not ok to go
back and reread omits if you haven't
done it for a couple weeks or months in
you come back to this
gravel preferences and read back through
my agreed upon the definitions uh...
had a career function
repetition is the key to getting get
this
so that gets us back to her were last
time
and let's go
back to creating an aspect up high file
failing to execute file yes
syntax care
uh... use the words doctor
scenery here's a puzzle carrot
certain of the syntax error in your code
and give you a syntax error traceback
in dollars and tax
it puts a little up at it looks like a
little
triad
arrow pointing up
wager area pecan
answer here
you have an extra parentheses in here so
he cleans you know the sprint senior
imagines that person leads to one in
five
so what we have here in our argument was
so you have your left practices started
right here
then you have a bearable variable
terrible so forth seperate by combines
and you've had it with front the ceo
over here
so if you have a pretty
tucked in here
that was the real into
so it's a comma separated without
so let's
open up s that top-line
and get back into our aspects
hope you feel more comfortable with
functions
aspect out fine
where to go back to you
where we were and all the start typing
and knocked up a student so i actually
go slow and often
fall on
add a comment at the top
to decode a plan x
paused pack
worker we're starting over for attorney
one i'm gonna get you back to everywhere
so you walk through it and hopefully
that helps you remember a little bit
rather just copying your files
it's good to go back through when you're
starting out so
the pledge pos pac aspect i need binary
files
is our first comments
we're gonna create function call
decoding so death decoding
and we passed it idea parameter
and we had
our documentation string
that was decipher
a aspect
datagram
binary
and print
the length of that city uh... length
alone
howie and
uh... proceeded up
so that's our first function worry wort
doesn't do much of the print the length
of the day to you passing
and then we had a main functions of
death main
this one doesn't take any parameters
just like the one that we are starting
off with before
starting
main
in quotes
then where do you just like we did
before opening or respect for our so
aspect
file equals open
sample taught us that
and aspect data equals
asked that underscore file elite
anti parentheses
well you are a complete on the verbal
names
there are definitely seen people have it
set up
it's a little complicated set
effectively
trying to avoid
extra complication
i'm not too snippets like ya so this is
awesome but there's also one that uh...
parts here variable names what you are
complete
uh... i clicked on
is part of that solution or with one of
them
yes gambling
through before we had some stuff that
knows about it
we're gonna just type it out
hope we'll get fatter
so then we had
some checking code were reviewed french
red
this many
fights
ali-han
aspect
to just like inside of our
of our decode function is it just sort
of placeholders that make sure that
we're doing the right thing
than women called decoded more passing
interest that they don't
and print
finishing
so again i have to print at the
beginning and my functions not because
you want that in your
you know final version of your code
but when you're defining its really nice
to see entering and exiting unique
function
so that you can follow the path that
would open up its called the father
really dig into the details of if
everything's the prints can often does
make life for these even
for the docking
let's go ahead
and give an account
so we really
will say in court
we should now have your aspect file
load up
you should say aspect
minute time
you can see all the different things
that are running around
for that and we have a decode
and me
yes from
word last function
uh... it back
at wickedly imported
if i hadn't imported
i think del aspect
so who's
and there's no aspect in there anymore
unless they ask that
you'll see the files that earlier and
that the variables
i think dot
all's going to let you prowess i
complete the fight
yes you have to have that
importance of imports asked that
and has had a look at all things that
could be aspect period
and one of those is the model is
important
silicon safety code
depresses
and he gets upset us because we do have
a arguments
hassen
soon if they ask that
and it's returned to us
the length of that
through the paper because function it
does
prints going to that variable
or any review media
they remember what you've imported if
you want to make a change every load
that these reloaded not import
t save reload
and that updates
from that source for these changed
let's try the main to so aspect
dot main
and this one will actually go vote a
file and do all everything for us
so that's actually gonna follow what's
in here so it's going to open the file
printout and then called the code for us
so it looks like it's working
so it's time to actually do more than
that because it just sort of a file we
have their let's go back and grab that
struck stuff that we did last time and
will start
decoding messages
so we're heading towards
being a load up one or more ass that's
been the one turning into a plot of the
ship track
for the chip that's our target
so let's go to our coherent had two
models ever any news
also import struct
just because you get my python
that doesn't mean you can get away from
it in new york python scripts
oh yes
so you want to know if you can put
decoder main first doesn't matter
in this case there's no says is not
using anything special and either one
but typically they could be any order
you want
so if you like a remains a top which
some people do
you're welcome to do that
my name's tennessee at the bottom of the
file to find out
i'm not sure why
all old habits
so import struct
import map
since we're gonna eventually want to do
some uh...
degrees geraniums in recent reads
and let's go work are
decode function
for the first thing over and i wanted to
you
we unpacked it before
so values
equal struct dot on hack
right out of the last lecture
seventeen d
sore on packing seventeen doubles
remember
she had seventeen variables
they were all typed double eight bytes
and then we need to go round
the right like the data off of our data
block if we give it the wrong size it's
gonna complain
and the size of that
was going to be
eight times
seventeen so eight bytes per double min
seventeen of them pool safety dot
zero colin
times
seventeen zero out the mapping almost
anywhere
if you're witty time seventeen years old
rather do it and i hadn't
time seventeen python works in my soul
calculator
and then we want to start
if you noticed when i get enter here
it didn't put me back
where i thought i would be
back over a values so this is a nice
indications something is not going on
i screwed up something
and what i missed was
array practicing
and you can see it does matching right
when you type it he jumps back to work
horses
or if you put the cursor on it
if you have the right mode central time
back and i like that account online
likable period
no it doesn't right away if you have
that motor north on the
match highway
right interpreting it
if you guys want to me that on so
helpful
and they were going to say
type of values
for grins will see what we get back to
type values
this is hope again tells us celeste
uh... values come back
and print
contents of values
and most variable he pass into print
get contacted turned into a string
might have always been the way you want
to look at it might be horrible looking
for at least of all print something else
mission to save values
and now we have
hopefully a list of seventeen items and
we can then fought the ones we know
this is timeless position zero px
intelligent
so we have this is hero
to you
and the sender should be sixteen
so we can grab them by numbers
vacancy time equals
values zero
and what it is within position
latitude
equals values
so formed
last time we also used every decision
trees to convert these annoying radians
around the earth into something which i
understand close to that
dvd for degrees equals math dot
degrees
latitude
and getting tired of typing longitude
people's values and that was in the
second position by that people
apparently portent
and ellen
this forty g_-forty treaties equals math
thought greens
wanted to
getting close here and then we want to
print out some results civil side
results colin
from our client come alive
degrees
degrees just watch out that's why com
acts
for the say reloaded
aspect
an aspect docking
and you should see
all diaper now which is really annoying
and what happened is we've proved that
was down
which was right in here
and so it dumped out zero to sixteen
positions inside of one packet
and we have
are weird
timestamp
and we have our radians around here
that are hard to interpret
turns out i didn't return right but i
thought of the alleged that the two port
to pull them less work very similar in
most cases if you're not trying to read
to them
so we have a basic functions at least
according to pack it now
there's lots of them in this final but
worshiper certainly get there
if you look at our results
we have our strange timestamp which is
in some youth and unsure of in seconds
but based
starting where i don't know
seconds of though
seconds from the g_p_s_ cmyk locally
just always won
and
missing you know what we carry
uh... painful
so here's our
are a lot of team
so how far murphy r
and here's
are negative ones too
which is showing that were way west
somewhere over alaska
yes the what minus one for instance came
from the minus two point five
yep
position to you
so let's turn this into a script that we
can run in several different ways more
effectively
i'd always going to remember which
function you're going to call
kind of annoying
it could be made you could call it
whatever
so let's turn this into a real function
so the first images from the bottom
escape
format a and then grade them
them the bottom of the file
and we've done this before
ring uses if name is main
and that says if this is being run as a
script we're gonna go ahead and call the
main function
so if
underscore underscore name
towards court
people's with two reports on and
single quotes
underscoring the score
underscore for often underscores today
and then print
starting
to ronan script
demo calming
and print
script
go ahead and say that
siva the top of the file
and we could have that one we had before
pound bang
user been
pmd python
that says if this gets ron start if i
dont reporter
go ahead and do that
now we need to tell us in the become
executed won't so if we do an ls dash
ellen here
we're going to see that are
uh... aspect upline
history here
it's r_w_ or are which means read write
read and read there's no executes a
anywhere
on this file to lead to make it execute
evil
sororities that crazy instruments each
blog
to make you execute won't
sold to you
xmission pointer bang
c_d_h_ maude plus acts process
please turn on the execute that
aspect top park
breast cancer
do an alice dash l
and take it look at the difference
between
so here's our before
and here's our after
so we've got
couple changes their taxes over here in
a lot for the permissions
and there's a little star over here
saying it's marked
the star for sixty four
so i think it's time to try and run it
so first will say xmission point disturb
shell scripts and aspect up five
press enter
fashion work great
hoops
exactly
in here it says
hears that their message state courts
posterity
looks when you tell bachelor program is
located
dot slash means the current directory
sophie go up my at that
spain
dot slash aspect alpine
press enter
cross our fingers and you should see a
script running
there's
contri
daughters occur directory
and so you gave it a swatch the
beginning and i gave you
dan rutz other filesystems should have
swatch and then stop that's going to
relative to the top of your desk
period is your current directory
forethought
and then a swatch means
her directory and then start doing
directories off of where you are right
now
and since we don't have a subdirectories
this is going to be
at that point
excellent question
facelift
so what happens is if they have a path
for if their search for stuff and it's
it's always going to look in places like
flash usr splotch been is the most
probably for
in river but i can really
there's type in the respect that shape
for search everywhere
and its search in your path and our path
is very carefully so that not be the
current directory for security reasons
a classically the people ac computers
before put
programs like ls
deducted
are actually a lot but i actually have
to computers
in a directory and then wait for u when
that retreated now i've spent a career
computer
it's happened so many times is painful
and so it just decided african tire
community of length
in installations that
the current directory is not in your
path
so it's a general security decision not
to have that so you won't have to talk
slash if you said really want to run
this program from the current directory
it is so easy to take a look and feel
that way
so we won't have to stay away
who was good programmers but not
not the folks are going to crack in the
thing to do that
we can either do dot sloshed
sis runs it through a shell script
or member because they were on aspect op
i
from
i pay for interpreter animal to the same
thing
this is a question to you our mass
pasteur fires you aspect i think
appear at the comment as you can write
you can use run um...
the bank may or may not work depending
on waypoints on the set up for you
there might not be about to go fine
i don't know there's probably
lots of her ways that's handled and it
may be in by default
i'm not a windows user so
you're on your own terms to find that
out there's a copy of ongoing without
now smith and stuff like that
thing casket
or actually jordan's also constructed
sites we've got a running scripts
and we need to start improving it
it remember last time and i'm gonna copy
this because i will most certainly make
a type of here
we're gonna copy the field lane so as
the people of these names
in order
such that we can use that we're dekhte
and zip
trick that
i suggested to stick in the file and
then you just be copy pasted
so we're gonna put back
variable appear
so we've got field names in their camera
modify our decode
so still going to have the values equals
but what we want to hand
right after that
so he's gonna let's kill everything
so i'm gonna do control space on the one
who has that prince type of values
scroll down
how it got section
from the sprint
that prints
control w
it's gone
say goodbye to it
control x two control ex in them just to
be to get back to my proffer
emmerdale
use this wine right here
so will say aspect
values equals dekhte
yield names
values
so believer from last time it has built
a dictionary
that has all of these names in it
as ducky
and then all of the values that we want
to go with it
all set up
and so it doesn't take me forever to
type i'm gonna copy
the lat long degrees we need to save
those keys into our dictionary so we've
got are nice
in decrees wrote the greens values
so he said especially for values
what degrees equals
snap dot degrees aspect values
wants to
so now rather for him to by number
do you really want to remember that
these
position to have asked that is what you
want to do
if that's what you see
i don't want to remember that
fidelity column by name
there we can say
results
we could just print out the dictionary
that's going to make a mess
let's try make a little bit prettier
it's a four
ke in
asked that values
if you have over a dictionary it's going
to take properties out one by one
you order i don't know what could be a
any order but
at least will come out one by one of the
can print them out
one on each line
couple spaces in their first
and then ki
aesthetic
values in the more you think he'll look
at the value for it
so we should see
in in some unknown order
uh... too much trouble role an organism
role and then the value and they'll pick
the next one might be why exploration
and give it the value
they should put them out one after the
other
thoughts do you have a different here so
this type one aspect
yet the orders pretty crazy it seems to
not be terribly
order by anything
that's okay at least they're they're and
nice
somewhat more readable form
the results and then here are all of our
values
so you can see here's what degrees
by name
so it's certainly become a little bit
more usable
and this is
not too far off of how i might approach
work or something to start simple and
try and build up slowly make sure easton
works
i'm gonna show you pretty print
thirty can say from
p prince
imports p prints and this is unfortunate
that the module and the function inside
the module are the same name
i think it's that they did this
it's confusing
pretty print model copy print inside of
it is a function called p friend for
pretty print we want that function
we now have a pretty print function that
you can say
p prints
and
sonar
so i have been there because you guys
don't okay
worry-free frank and it will look better
than
dot so will go to the top
and as always good to have all a very
important one place at the top
so from
p print import p print
so now we're going to go ahead and
change our decode function to return
that and where do the print from the
main retarded coat function should be
printing to the screen
it should just be building a dictionary
and getting you back addiction that you
decided to print it
having your decode print everything is
really inflexible and one of the altar
do something what i feel like they kick
him elsewhere just what the dictionary
back
work towards that
and the key thing is being
early on here and changed the last
couple lines
sophie go scroll down our to argue cohen
rental weeks
from the print
results four key and the printed
antiques line delete those
control w
effective yeltsin's gone
and we want
return
aspect
values you don't need that comment
that's after it goes down here just
helping us out
so if we do that is considered printing
out the dictionary it's going to return
it back and we can then use it
in our main function
sonar main functions to get improved so
we do something with
the return
siva four weeks called decode who
actually want to deal with what comes
back sourcesafe datagram which is what
have you both and refers to a pack of
data from a summer
or sensor
today graham equals decode will use that
p prints
on t_v_ graham
so we could have done print datagram it
would've worked but
maybe kinda ugly
and so it's trying on that and see what
happens
source a run
if you look it's actually not that bad
it's very similar to what we did before
there's a little bit different
formatting
p print them we did that poorly
but they tried to make p print sort of
for things like this at our big unless
they can help you out making a nicer
and actually looks like it's ordered
them which is nice it looks like they're
in alphabetical order so it's a little
bit easier finder stopped if we'd wanted
to sort them ourselves if we could have
deal headlines of folk later
we don't need a lot of people right
pretty print is that i have good that
will function held up your sleeve
leading without icon data structures
like dictionaries in listserv like that
will help you
you've there without being
clobbered by just
things that wrap around a wine store
artery
for actually getting
we're getting along pretty good
unfortunately were at a time for today
so we're gonna keep going return this
function
into
something back
we can use what we can pick any datagram
right now we're just reading that first
one or stock going from zero
through the first seventeen
and what we want to be able to do is
rap any datagram out of there
and often they'll figure out how to get
a grand jury file on the block across
all of them
and start doing something interesting
with mike
ml and what i think you can see i asked
for
if you would you like to be able to do
with this down the road is build up an
aspect in the trade
you could run it it would entail where
the ship was you may be valid record for
ten thousand aspect files from the last
couple years cruises
you could then
lateral script that went through all
those and then a summary of
worried ship went
and how long it spent
surveying
you know it's coverage
went to get through all this
yeah she's really powerful